

Andrii Latyshev

Software Engineer



Software Engineer with 5+ years of experience in development of enterprise applications (Java + Oracle DB).

My experience covers full delivery process: collection of requirements directly from customers, creation of design, implementation, bug-fixing, support, delivery installation patch to customer environment, on-site production support.

My main goal to be excellent T-shaped professional who can make products with high quality and support each step during creation.

Also have experience in onsite\online production supports, E2E process troubleshooting, performance analysis.





in https://andrylat.dev/

Work Experience

May 2021 - present

Software Engineer at intive

December 2015 - May 2021

Senior Software Engineer at Netcracker

Java, PL/SQL developer on NetCracker implementation project for product integration into IT/OSS structure of Service Provider in Swiss.

- Developing new features based on Netcracker Platform.
- Refactoring and bug-fixing legacy code.
- Developing SOAP\Rest web services, JMS based and file based integration interfaces using Java and PL/SQL
- Making performance analysis and troubleshooting, data migration
- SVT and E2E testing support
- Working with customers at analysis and design stages, participating in design documents preparation.
- Design and estimation preparation
- On-site production support

Most Java code was written for the Netcracker Product platform which has its own API and functionality.

The main goal of Application was equipment inventory and providing information about this telecom equipment. Also Application must manage orders which change equipment statuses and connections, manage customers which are using equipment, bandwidth and so on.

I was a part of Agile team which works directly with customer and their operation teams. My responsibilities included not only development, but the entire development cycle of a feature. First, needs to collect requirements either from responsible designers or from users directly. Then prepare solution design, approve it with customers and then describe solution detailed design. Next, needs to think over the implementation, assess the risks and impact on performance, and only then start implementation. When the feature is ready, it goes to QA team, where support is needed in case of any misunderstandings. Further, according to the schedule of monthly production installations, the feature goes to E2E testing, and then to production, where support, bug fixing and improvements may be required.

Personal Mentor at MentorCruise

Personal mentoring with Java tach stack.

- Personal course development
- Code reviews
- Task management
- Real-life project simulation

MentorCruise helps me to share my knowledge and experience with other students, who starts or continue learning of programming.

I provide set of tasks for student according to his requirements and goals. After it we discuss them, approve and start the path.

During the path, I make review of code, fix it and explain where problems are. More than 15 students, 3 directions of development (Oracle DB, Java and Spring).

August 2019 - February 2021

Mentor at FoxmindEd

Mentoring students according to school course.

- Code Review
- Help with different questions and job finding

FoxmindEd is learning center for developers. My specialization was Java and databases. FoxmindEd provided set of tasks for student which covers Java SE, Java EE, Spring, JPA, Hibernate and Swagger topics. My main responsibility was to accompany a student: make code review, support him with his questions, explain unclear points and so on.

More than 60 students were, more than 1100 code reviews were done during one year.

Education



2014 - 2018

Institute of refrigeration, cryotechnology and ecoenergetics named after V. S. Martynovsky Computer Science, Cybersecutiry

Skills

- Java
- Oracle DB
- PL/SQL
- javaEE
- Agile & Waterfall Methodologies
- Docker
- SOAP
- REST

Languages

- English Intermediate
- Russian Native or Bilingual
- Ukrainian Native or Bilingual

Powered by **CakeResume**